MOSES OSHO

44 Welsford Street, London, SE1 5RA · 07950911288 mosho@live.co.uk · LinkedIn · GitHub

I am an ambitious and highly analytical full stack software developer with experience working in Ruby and JavaScript. A graduate of Makers Academy with previous experience within the sales and market research sphere. I was drawn to software development as a career because it's at the centre of everything we do, from phone apps to websites and programs that we take for granted on a daily basis. It's because of this importance that it is used in almost every industry which I feel suits a multipotentialite such as myself. Giving room to explore different interests and industries whilst also suiting my skillset, with the room for continual learning which I enjoy. My background in freelance music production has given me the valuable ability to think creatively which I also apply to software development. I'm currently looking into the uses of A.I in my spare time and how they're being used to impact different industries and generally improve quality of life.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

JUL 2022 - NOV 2022

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP, MAKERS ACADEMY

An intensive 16-week software development course focusing on:

- Object-Oriented Programming, Test Driven Development, Agile methodologies and S.O.L.I.D principles.
- Communication and empathy were vital when collaborating with other team members via pair programming and use of GitHub as version control for group projects.
- Designed and built web applications primarily in Ruby and JavaScript, relying heavily on problem solving and attention to detail to do this effectively.
- Deployment of web applications using a light cloud service such as Heroku.
- Learnt a consistent debugging process to resolve issues.
- Used communication skills and self-led learning to build a mobile phone app in React Native with my team
- My ability to learn was crucial as emphasis was placed on self-led learning to becoming tech-agnostic and able to learn new languages in very short timeframes.

PROJECTS:

- Wakify <u>GitHub</u> A mobile phone application that matches your mood to a Spotify playlist. Built with React Native, AsyncStorage, CSS. Tested with Cypress and Jest.
- Acebook <u>GitHub</u> A social media application similar to Facebook, with the ability to post, comment like posts and add friends. Built with Node.js, MongoDB, Express, handlebars, HTML and CSS. Tested with Jest and cypress.
- Chitter <u>GitHub</u> A social media application similar to twitter. Built with Ruby, Sinatra, and PSQL. Tested with RSpec.

Technologies: Ruby, JavaScript, Node.js, React, React Native, HTML, CSS, PSQL, MongoDB, RSpec, Jest, Cypress, Express, Handlebars

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEC 2021 - PRESENT

JUST EAT/UBER EATS, DELIVERY COURIER - LONDON

- Picked my own shifts and managed time by finding optimum delivery routes to customers.
- Paid attention to detail with company delivery policies, alcohol age checks and customer delivery requests.

 Utilized communication end to end when interacting with customers ensuring great customer service and restaurant employees to ensure foot is delivered correctly, Resulting in a 100% customer satisfaction rate in over 100 orders.

MAR 2018 - PRESENT

FREELANCE MUSIC PRODUCER/SOUND ENGINEER, SELF EMPLOYED - LONDON

- Used time management to complete commission-based work such as arranged studio sessions.
- Learnt to market through social media to reach clients and collaborators internationally.
- Communicating and working with other producers and artists to create projects.
- Adaptable for client input and preference.
- Meticulous attention to detail when removing unwanted sonic artifacts similar to debugging.
- Stripe integration and designing a web store to meet customer needs and make purchasing process as smooth as possible.
- Communicating, interpersonal skills and problem solving when working with brands such as
 Football Beyond Borders and WOW HYDRATE creating sync music for their video adverts and
 content.
- Audio engineering on set for shoots with brands such as Football Beyond Borders and WOW HYDRATE.
- Attention to detail when negotiating work and rates.

MAR 2016 - APR 2017

MARKET RESEARCH ANALYST, QUALIFA - BRIGHTON

- Communicated and displayed empathy with highly qualified IT professionals regarding the latest IT data and technology.
- Contact research and data handling for outsourcing using Salesforce and LinkedIn.
- Interpersonal skills were important when building relationships with outsourcings, especially on LinkedIn.
- Awareness of GDPR and various non-disclosure agreements.

EDUCATION

2008 - 2015

GCSE AND A LEVELS, CITY OF LONDON ACADEMY

- 13 A*- C GCSE grades including English, Maths and Triple Science.
- A Levels in Biology, Chemistry and Maths.

INTERESTS

- Currently looking at the latest advancements and technology such as the use of A.I in different industries such as ChatGPT and A.I generated images.
- Qualified first aider with St John's ambulance. Empathy, communication and attention to detail were of upmost importance in the training as we learnt to deal with people in crisis and creating a safe space.
- Other hobbies include music, football, gym, advertising and marketing.